president Trump's state of the union was
a masterclass in leadership but some
liberals missed out by refusing to
attend the Democrats who are boycotting
that we know of so far the familiy
jayapala Washington
Seattle's representative giant Paul also
boycotted Trump's inauguration and joint
session and before that she spent years
as an immigrant rights activist in short
she's the worst of the worst mr. speaker
is an immigrant myself I am tired of
being called the worst of the worst well
if she won't go to Washington I'll bring
the State of the Union to her I just
walked into representative John Paul's
office and nothing can stop me from
giving her a piping hot dose of truth oh
she's in a meeting
15 minutes of waiting calmed me down so
I'll start with a softball I heard we
had something in common we were both
born in Indiana India oh you're from
India yeah that's my mistake I always
assumed the best of people I've heard
enough hold on one second
since you want to attend the State of
the Union I've brought the state of the
union to you because what you're doing
is not normal this is normal this is not
a normal presidency hold on ladies and
gentlemen this interview will commence I
really feel like the racism and the
hatred that's coming out of the White
House does not allow me to be in that
chamber do you have a designated
survivor for this interview I do not
minds Kiefer Sutherland you might think
locking a TV star in the car would
restore normalcy but by skipping the
State of the Union the congresswoman is
defying one of the sacred norms that
makes our democracy work the State of
the Union is a speech it's one speech
but I don't think that this is a
president where you can count on
anything he says one day he's supportive
of the dreamers the next day he's not
one day he says Mexico is gonna pay for
the wall the next day it's clear that
tax payers are gonna pay for the wall I
think he's really made a mockery out of
that office and I think therefore the
State of the Union you say the president
has made a mockery out of the State of
the Union but I say the state of the
state of our union is strong
[Applause]
[Music]
I completely disagree that the state of
the union is strong this president is
undermining every institution that
provides a check and a balance so I
guess you're fine with speeches when
you're giving them but without watching
the State of the Union how will she know
the State of the Union I'm gonna be
attending a gathering that's the state
of our union with 500 activists and
leaders who are gonna celebrate our
unity and put forward our vision of
where we want to go in the world do you
think at a gathering like that there
will be so much virtuous signaling that
you can see it from space I think that
it will be an amazing bright light in a
very dim time so you will be able to see
it from space got it so she planned her
own State of the Union surely the people
of Seattle wouldn't follow her lead here
we go
are you both gonna be attending the
State of the Union this year no no so
you're not personally attending the
State of the Union it's gonna be in
Washington DC if you were gonna attend I
think you would probably know by now her
resistance has trickled down to her
constituents and not only that other
Democrats are boycotting as well this is
not normal I have to restore order
what would the State of the Union - the
State of the Union always comes with a
rebuttal so I want to give you an
opportunity to respond to any of my
criticisms go ahead well I'd like to say
that I think that one of the great
opportunities of our democracy is
peaceful protest and I refuse to be
complicit
I refuse to be silent and I am going to
stand up against this president and the
ways in which he is destroying who we
are as a country
[Music]
yeah I'm boycotting that you can't
expect me to just sit around and pretend
this is normal
[Music]